{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "The main artery leaving the left side of the heart and carrying freshly oxygenated blood to the body.",
			"back": "aorta"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "The smallest branches of arteries leading to the vast network of capillaries.",
			"back": "arterioles"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "A blood vessel, consisting of three layers of tissue and smooth muscle, that carries blood away from the heart.",
			"back": "artery"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "The small blood vessels that connect arterioles and venules; various substances pass through capillary walls, into and out of the interstitial fluid, and then on to the cells.",
			"back": "capillaries"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "The formation of clots to plug openings in injured blood vessels and stop blood flow.",
			"back": "coagulation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "A bruise from an injury that causes bleeding beneath the skin without breaking the skin; also see ecchymosis.",
			"back": "contusion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "A buildup of blood beneath the skin that produces a characteristic blue or black discoloration as the result of an injury.",
			"back": "ecchymosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "A nosebleed.",
			"back": "epistaxis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "Vomiting blood.",
			"back": "hematemesis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "A mass of blood that has collected within damaged tissue beneath the skin or in a body cavity.",
			"back": "hematoma"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "Blood in the urine.",
			"back": "hematuria"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "A hereditary condition in which the patient lacks one or more of the bloodâ€™s normal clotting factors.",
			"back": "hemophilia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "The coughing up of blood.",
			"back": "hemoptysis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "Bleeding.",
			"back": "hemorrhage"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "A dressing impregnated with a chemical compound that slows or stops bleeding by assisting with clot formation.",
			"back": "hemostatic dressing"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "A condition in which the circulatory system fails to provide sufficient circulation to maintain normal cellular function; also called shock.",
			"back": "hypoperfusion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "A condition in which low blood volume, due to massive internal or external bleeding or extensive loss of body water, results in inadequate perfusion.",
			"back": "hypovolemic shock"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "A device that provides proximal compression of severe bleeding near the axial or inguinal junction with the torso.",
			"back": "junctional tourniquet"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "Black, foul-smelling, tarry stool containing digested blood.",
			"back": "melena"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "A life-threatening fracture of the pelvis caused by a force that displaces one or both sides of the pelvis laterally and posteriorly.",
			"back": "open-book pelvic fracture"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "A device to splint the bony pelvis to reduce hemorrhage from bone ends, venous disruption, and pain.",
			"back": "pelvic binder"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "The flow of blood through body tissues and vessels.",
			"back": "perfusion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-23",
			"front": "A condition in which the circulatory system fails to provide sufficient circulation to maintain normal cellular functions; also called hypoperfusion.",
			"back": "shock"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-24",
			"front": "The bleeding control method used when a wound continues to bleed despite the use of direct pressure; useful if a patient is bleeding severely from a partial or complete amputation.",
			"back": "tourniquet"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-25",
			"front": "Narrowing of a blood vessel.",
			"back": "vasoconstriction"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-26",
			"front": "The blood vessels that carry blood from the tissues to the heart.",
			"back": "veins"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-26-tag-vocabulary-card-27",
			"front": "Very small, thin-walled blood vessels.",
			"back": "venules"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-26",
		"label": "Chapter 26"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}